<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[The Wylde Chronicles]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[The Wylde Chronicles]]></description>
        <link>http://www.thewyldechronicles.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 22:29:38 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://www.thewyldechronicles.com/chapters-feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 22:29:32 GMT</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hour of The Village]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Non-time in the Southwest - The time of the village is 4:30 in the afternoon.  This is the time that I’m really feeling the village.  Feeling what a village feels like.  It’s that time of the day where there is a pause between the hard work done out on the land during the meat of the day and the time that we all gather for dinner.  There is the generally satisfied air of a day well spent that permeates the energy of the tribe.]]></description>
            <link>http://www.thewyldechronicles.com/anake/hour-of-the-village.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thewyldechronicles.com/anake/hour-of-the-village.html</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeremiah]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Place That Is Not a Place]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[A Blindfolded Day, Part 2 - I’m a few hours into a 24-hour blindfold challenge. I’m experiencing very clear vision behind my blindfold.  I’m finding it disturbingly close to what I know of the “actual reality” but not quite the same.  It’s an uncanny valley that I’m not crossing.]]></description>
            <link>http://www.thewyldechronicles.com/anake/the-place-that-is-not-a-place.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thewyldechronicles.com/anake/the-place-that-is-not-a-place.html</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeremiah]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2015 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Only in Silence the Word]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[A Blindfolded Day, Part 1 - Still in my sleeping bag I place the folded bandana over my eyes and tie it behind my head.  The pre-dawn greyness is replaced with inky blackness.  I won’t be removing this bandana, I hope, until I hear the wake up song tomorrow morning.  Between now and then lies 300 miles and 24 hours of unseen and unforeseen experiences.]]></description>
            <link>http://www.thewyldechronicles.com/anake/only-in-silence-the-word.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thewyldechronicles.com/anake/only-in-silence-the-word.html</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeremiah]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2015 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Scrappy Ninja]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[A Game of Capture the Flag - We’re about 30 minutes into a game of capture the flag.  I’m currently “guarding” our flag.  My clothing is shades of mottled green and my face is streaked with mud and soot.  My shirt has homemade fringe running down the arms.  Supposedly I’m camouflaged, but I feel as visible as a hot pink air balloon in crisp blue sky.  And I feel immobilized because of it.]]></description>
            <link>http://www.thewyldechronicles.com/anake/the-scrappy-ninja.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thewyldechronicles.com/anake/the-scrappy-ninja.html</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeremiah]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Thank You For This Moment]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Thanksgiving Address Reflection - Thank you for reading this.  I want to recognize the importance of that.  The "if a tree falls in the woods and there's no one there to hear it, is there a sound?" question applies equally to written words.  If there is no one reading them, are bits and bytes really words?  How much of existence is in quantum superposition, decohered into concreteness only when *you* see it?  Thank you for decohering this writing into concrete existence.]]></description>
            <link>http://www.thewyldechronicles.com/anake/thank-you-for-this-moment.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thewyldechronicles.com/anake/thank-you-for-this-moment.html</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeremiah]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Babbling Brook]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Sense Meditation Reflection - What has occured to me, and this is fascinating, is that I previously didn't actually know what the stream sounded like.  Since I didn't know what it sounded like there was no way I could hear it before I saw it.  I mean, really, I knew what a stream sounds like.  I've heard lots of streams in my day.  But either I didn't know what *this* stream sounded like.  Or I didn't know what pieces of the sound of a stream sounded like.  And when you are further away and there are other noises all you might hear is a piece of a stream sound.  Now I know a bit more what the components of stream sound are, so I might hear just one babble and realize, "oh, a babbling brook."]]></description>
            <link>http://www.thewyldechronicles.com/anake/the-babbling-brook.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thewyldechronicles.com/anake/the-babbling-brook.html</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeremiah]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dirt Medicine]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Sit Spot Reflection - I’ve known for some time that my energy is recharged the most by being immersed in nature. This is the first time I’ve successfully had a practice where the intention is just that. And that says a lot.]]></description>
            <link>http://www.thewyldechronicles.com/anake/dirt-medicine.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thewyldechronicles.com/anake/dirt-medicine.html</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeremiah]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2014 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rocketships are Rad]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[An Introduction... - My name is Jeremiah. I'm a current student of the Anake program class of 2015. I’d like to introduce myself and tell you the story about how I ended up here. However, when I tell that story it no longer makes sense because here is not where I thought it was. Strangely, it's where I wanted it to be, without knowing. I'm really not sure how I ended up here, but with great fortune it's exactly where I need to be. Clear as the fresh spring waters of the Cascades? No doubt.]]></description>
            <link>http://www.thewyldechronicles.com/anake/rocketships-are-rad.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thewyldechronicles.com/anake/rocketships-are-rad.html</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeremiah]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2014 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Poop, Fire, and Land]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Field Course at Boulder Outdoor Survival School (BOSS)]]></description>
            <link>http://www.thewyldechronicles.com/nomad/poop-fire-and-land.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thewyldechronicles.com/nomad/poop-fire-and-land.html</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeremiah]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2011 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Glimpse]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[A Visit to Teaching Drum Wilderness School]]></description>
            <link>http://www.thewyldechronicles.com/nomad/glimpse.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thewyldechronicles.com/nomad/glimpse.html</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeremiah]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2010 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>